# MICHAEL KOLESIDIS

### FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

### **Profile**

I am a Front-End Web Developer with a diverse background in computer science, economics and the arts. I enjoy being creative and curious, learning and building new, exciting things every day. I am passiotate with frontend development and I aim at creating web experiences that are both functional and beautiful.

### Tech Stack

### **Programming/Scripting Languages**



JavaScript CSS











Web Dev Frameworks, Libraries & More











React Software & Tools



















Linux Illustrator XD Photoshop Figma VSCode \* Basic knowledge

## Sample Projects

JavaScript Software Synthesizer 🜍 🌐 The JavaScript Software Synthesizer is a web application

enabling you to make and play music in the browser. It is a software synthesizer utilizing the Web Audio API by implementing a variety of JavaScript libraries.

Technologies: Tone.js, JavaScript, Sass, npm

### Landmarks 🗘 🌐

A React web application showing landmarks around the globe. It fetches data from a static dataset, and generates a set of card elements using props, as well as conditional rendering.

Technologies: React, JavaScript, Webpack, npm

### 3D Cube 🗘 🌐

A 3D cube rotating according to mouse movement. It is created dynamically on load, according to window dimensions.

Technologies: p5.js, JavaScript

### Japanese Restaurant 🗘 🌐

A JavaScript single-page application (SPA) showcasing the use of ES6 modules as well as Webpack.

Technologies: JavaScript, Sass, Webpack, npm

### Minesweeper Emoji 🗘 🌐

The classic game reimagined and implemented with emojis.

Technologies: p5.js, JavaScript

### Sports App ( )

A progressive web app allows the user to create tables,

Technologies: JavaScript, CSS

### Contact



michaelkolesidis in michaelkolesidis

michaelkolesidis.com/

michael.kolesidis@gmail.com

+306976941600 (Greece) +447365113313 (UK)

### Education

### University of Macedonia

MSc Applied Informatics (Ongoing) Thessaloniki, Greece

#### University of Macedonia

**BSc Economics** Thessaloniki, Greece

#### Universitat de Barcelona

BSc Economics (Exchange Student) Barcelona, Spain

#### **University of Sussex**

BA (Hons) Drama: Theatre and Performance Brighton, United Kingdom

### Certificates

#### Social Hackers Academy

Frontend Web Development Certificate

#### University of Sussex

General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

#### **University of Sussex**

Diversity in the Workplace

### **Experience**

#### Freelancer

Front-End Web Developer Feb 2022 - Present

#### Social Hackers Academy

Student Mentor Mar 2022 - Present

#### **Manning Publications**

Live Project Beta Tester / Book Reviewer

Nov 2021 - Present

### Languages

**Greek (Native)** 

**English (Proficient)** 

Spanish (Intermediate)

German (Basic)

